# Rajvinder Grewal

## Sr. QA Manager - Shipcom Wireless Inc

Houston, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Rajvinder-Grewal/a23de1c7bc3cfd6b

• More than 8 years of experience in Managing and performing Quality Assurance testing which includes manual and

automation System Integration Testing for mobile as well as web applications with strong understanding of technical

details, data analysis, data mapping, handset testing as well as cellular network planning, optimization and field testing.

- Experienced in managing QA software testing team(s) for over five years including offshore resources.
- Successfully lead QA team(s) on manual and automation QA testing, performing complete life cycle of application(s)

testing which includes unit, integration, regression, functional, non-functional, black box, white box testing(s) as well

as defect tracking, reporting, requirement review and overall interactions with various teams involved as SPOC.

• Experienced in identifying test cases, defining test objectives, executing test plans, creating traceability matrices while

following project management methodologies like Agile (Scrum), Waterfall or Hybrid with excellent understanding of

the Software Development Life Cycle.

• Expert in using various automation testing tools like Telerik Test Studio, TFS, Selenium WebDrivers, QTP, UFT,

Quality Center ALM 11.0, Test Director with main responsibilities of - designing, building, maintaining and executing

the automation framework/scripts to perform front-end GUI testing & navigation testing of application(s) in cross

browser compatibility testing. And performing load as well as performance testing using Telerik, LoadRunner & Jmeter.

• Highly skilled in using mobile automation and testing tools like Device Anywhere and Perfecto Mobile while performing GUI testing as well as regression testing on various different mobile operating systems like iOS, Android,

Windows and Blackberry.

• Experienced in using WireShark, QXDM, QPST, QCAT, QMICM, Samsung PST, Motorola RSD, LGUP and other

OEM specific product support tools for run time analysis and collection of device logs along with using SQL queries

for verification & validation of backend testing.

 Lead Verizon's OMADM-IOT certification testing for all 4G-LTE Android device OEM submissions which includes major prime vendors like Samsung, LG, Motorola, HTC, Sony Mobile and Kyocera Mobile.

- Experienced in working effectively with client submissions, multiple internal teams, outsourced teams, project managers, Federal government leadership and contracting teams.
- Proactive learner combined with good technical, analytical and leadership skills with agile problem solving approach.
- · Highly motivated team leader with excellent communication, presentation and interpersonal skills.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Sr. QA Manager

Shipcom Wireless Inc - Houston, TX - March 2015 to Present

#### **QA Manager**

Verizon Wireless - Township of Warren, NJ - February 2012 to February 2015

## **Protocol Testing Engineer**

LTE - South Plainfield, NJ - June 2011 to January 2012

#### **QA Team Lead**

Samsung Telecommunications (R&D) - Bridgewater, NJ - March 2010 to June 2011

## RF Engineer

GTL Limited - July 2009 to February 2010

## **Software Testing Engineer**

Dibon Solutions - Dallas, TX - February 2009 to June 2009

## **Associate RF Engineer**

Mobile Comm. Professionals Inc - Plano, TX - May 2008 to August 2008

# **Technical Support Officer**

Dell Canada Inc - Edmonton, AB - September 2006 to July 2007

#### Assistant Network Operations at B.S.N.L

Punjab Telecomm. Circle - Chandigarh, Chandigarh - January 2004 to July 2004

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Electrical Engineering in Telecommunication

Cleveland State University - Cleveland, OH

#### **Telecommunications**

Humber Institute of Technology - Toronto, ON

# Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Comm. Engg

Punjab Technical University

# LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajvinder-grewal-371a1a11